Michael Henry

Software Engineer Boston, MA https://github.com/aigyptios/

Empathetic front-end software engineer with over five years' experience building interactive JavaScript web applications. I have strong skills in modern, progressive web development with HTML5, CSS, JS, and React, a passion for writing clean, modular, and efficient code, an eye for user-centered design, excellent communication skills, and extensive experience working on Agile teams.

Experience

Clarity Innovations, Boston, MA (Remote)

May 2020 - Present

Software Engineer II

- Pair program to build mission-critical application with React, Material UI, GraphQL, Kotlin, Spring, and Postgres.
- Tests written in Jest, Enzyme, JUnit, and Cypress. Refactored legacy back end and APIs according to best practices.
- Collaborate with UX designers, product managers, and software engineers to plan and execute application roadmap.

Vivante Health, Athens, Greece; Boston, MA (Remote)

February 2020 - March 2020

- Software Engineer
- Worked closely within Scrum team to add new features to customer-facing Angular 8, ngrx application, GIThrive.
- Interfaced with teams distributed between Athens, Greece and remotely throughout the United States.

Liberty Mutual Insurance, Boston, MA

September 2017 - September 2018

Senior Front End Web Developer

- Built Dojo 1 components for the customer-facing auto insurance sales application, tested with Jasmine and Selenium.
- Partnered with UX Design team on user experience research, persona creation, and iterative prototyping, turning mockups into interactive high-fidelity React and Redux applications used for live user testing.

Publicis Sapient, Boston, MA

July 2014 - September 2017

Senior Interactive Developer, Interactive Developer II, Interactive Developer I

- Established a protocol for streamlined design system development in SCSS from an atomic design-based prototype.
- Built a modular, responsive jQuery UI widget for an AJAX-based web portal with D3.js visualizations.
- Single-handedly developed a large-scale dynamic spreadsheet component in Ember. js to be used across multiple work streams for a top-tier international financial services corporation in Boston.

Computer Science Department, Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA

September 2013 - May 2014

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Graded and reviewed materials 3 – 4 hours weekly for about 20 students per semester for two CS courses.

Education

Boston College (05/2014)

GPA: 3.891/4, summa cum laude B.A. in Computer Science, Theology (Honors) Honors Program, Dean's List, Neuhauser Award in CS, Sophomore Scholar Award in CS

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki (09/2018 - 06/2019)

GPA: 9.13/10

School of Modern Greek Language, B2 Certificate Program

Skills

Code: JavaScript, Typescript, JSX, HTML5, SCSS, Java, Kotlin, SQL, React, GraphQL, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, Redux, Angular, npm, git, JIRA, Pivotal Tracker, Gitlab, XP, object-oriented programming, design systems, Material Design, MV*, BEM (CSS), SMACSS (CSS), Agile, Scrum

Languages:

Egyptian Arabic (basic, native bilingual) Greek (intermediate proficiency) French (basic) Spanish (basic)